<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>PR - Tag - leo.fm</title><link>https://leo.fm/tags/pr/</link><description>PR - Tag - leo.fm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</managingEditor><webMaster>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright 2022 Leo Laporte, all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 11:21:18 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo.fm/tags/pr/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>PR Info</title><link>https://leo.fm/pr/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 11:21:18 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/pr/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Leo Laporte and the TWiT Network can offer your clients unequaled exposure to technology consumers, early-adopters, and influencers in a number of ways.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Leo hosts <em><a href="http://techguylabs.com/">The Tech Guy,</a></em> a national radio show on technology syndicated by the <a href="http://premrad.com/">Premiere Networks</a>. The show is recorded every Saturday and Sunday from 2-5p Eastern. It also airs on 200+ stations nationwide including KFI Los Angeles and KSFO San Francisco with an Average Quarter Hour audience of 500,000.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Leo produces and hosts the most listened to tech podcasts in the world with more than six million unique downloads each month, at <a href="http://twit.tv/">TWiT.tv</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>His IPTV network, <a href="http://twitlive.tv/">TWiT Live</a>, broadcasts 50+ hours a week of live streaming video which is watched by several million people every month.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Leo has among the largest social networks of any tech journalist in the world with more than 500,000 followers on <a href="http://twitter.com/leolaporte">Twitter</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Leo makes regular appearances on mainstream radio and television shows as a commentator. He has appeared more than a dozen times on <em>Live with Regis and Kelly</em>. Other appearances include CNN, The Today Show, and NPR&rsquo;s <em>All Things Considered</em>.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>For more information about Leo, including a head shot, visit his <a href="/bio/" rel="">Bio</a>.</p>
<h3>Contacting Leo</h3>Please no phone calls. The best way to stay in touch is to email press releases and information to <a href="mailto:pr@twit.tv?subject=Press%20Release%20-">pr@twit.tv</a>.
<p>If you&rsquo;d like to send products for review you may mail them to TWiT, 1351 Redwood Way, Suite B, Petaluma, CA 94954. We usually keep software and return hardware after a short review period, but if you want your product back, you <em>must</em> include a pre-paid return shipping label. Leo does not sign NDAs or honor embargoes, so please wait until your product has been released before offering it for review.</p>
<p>We rarely interview vendors about their products or take vendor meetings. However, we are always interested in interviewing content creators, technologists, and industry thought-leaders. You may send guest pitches to <a href="mailto:pitches@twit.tv?subject=Guest%20Pitch%20-"><a href="mailto:pitches@twit.tv" rel="">pitches@twit.tv</a></a>. To request an interview with Leo, email <a href="mailto:requests@twit.tv?subject=Interview%20Request%20-"><a href="mailto:requests@twit.tv" rel="">requests@twit.tv</a></a>.</p>
<p>Thanks for your interest!</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>