<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>life - Tag - leo.fm</title><link>https://leo.fm/tags/life/</link><description>life - Tag - leo.fm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</managingEditor><webMaster>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright 2022 Leo Laporte, all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 10:16:11 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo.fm/tags/life/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Life is Short</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/08/bullshit/</link><pubDate>Sat, 29 Aug 2020 10:16:11 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/08/bullshit/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I love <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paul_Graham_%28programmer%29" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Paul Graham</a>’s essays. <a href="http://paulgraham.com/vb.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">This one</a>, from 2016, truly hits home.</p>
<p>Life is short, so it’s worth eliminating the time wasters. For one, defending yourself online.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Your instinct when attacked is to defend yourself.  But like a lot of instincts, this one wasn&rsquo;t designed for the world we now live in.  Counterintuitive as it feels, it&rsquo;s better most of the time not to defend yourself.  Otherwise these people are literally taking your life.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But that’s just one of many powerful ideas in this essay. Please take 10 of your precious remaining minutes  to read it.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One heuristic for distinguishing stuff that matters is to ask yourself whether you&rsquo;ll care about it in the future.  Fake stuff that matters usually has a sharp peak of seeming to matter.  That&rsquo;s how it tricks you.  The area under the curve is small, but its shape jabs into your consciousness like a pin.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As I come to the waning years of my life, I want to make every minute count.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Relentlessly prune bullshit, don&rsquo;t wait to do things that matter, and savor the time you have.  That&rsquo;s what you do when life is short.</p>
</blockquote>]]></description></item></channel></rss>