<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>health - Tag - leo.fm</title><link>https://leo.fm/tags/health/</link><description>health - Tag - leo.fm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</managingEditor><webMaster>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright 2022 Leo Laporte, all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo.fm/tags/health/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Perfect Fit</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/07/maskfitters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/07/maskfitters/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>My 3D printed custom mask fitters have arrived and they’re swell!</p>
<p>Remember my post from last month about <a href="https://leo.fm/2020/06/improved/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">creating a mask fitter using Belus3D</a>?</p>
<p>Well they’re arrived and I have to say they really work. The idea is that the fitter, contoured perfectly to your face thanks to the software generated model, seals the mask material around your mouth and nose so that no air escapes around the edges. You are  breathing only through the mask.</p>
<p>I’ve ordered about eight of them from three different companies. All three specialize in printing dental implants. I used the three featured on the <a href="https://bellus3d.com/solutions/mask-fitter-order" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Belus3D ordering page</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cadmusdental.com/cadmus-store/mask-fitters" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Cadmus Dental</a> took almost a month to get me the two designs I ordered - the tall and premium fitters.</p>
<p><a href="https://masterlaboratories.com/product/bellus3d-mask-fitter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Master Labs</a> took less than a week, but they’re local. I was only able to order the standard design from them.</p>
<p>I’m still waiting for the fitters I ordered from <a href="https://www.forecast3d.com/services/bellus3d-mask-fitter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Forecast3D</a> but I think they’re on their way. If you’re in a hurry go with Master Labs.</p>
<p>All the fitters are printed from PLA plastic and seem pretty durable. The Standard fitter is all you need. All cost roughly $20 each.</p>
<p>This is me using the Master Labs Standard fitter over one of my homemade cloth masks.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="https://leo.fm/images/maskfitter.png" title=" Leo wearing the standard mask fitter " data-thumbnail="https://leo.fm/images/maskfitter.png" data-sub-html="<h2>Go ahead, come at me Covid!</h2><p> Leo wearing the standard mask fitter </p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Go ahead, come at me Covid!</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>According to Belus3D</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The NIH has listed the Bellus3D Mask Fitter as <a href="https://3dprint.nih.gov/discover/3dpx-013836" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">appropriate for clinical use</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Loma Linda University School of Dentistry has worked with [Belus3d] on the development and testing of the Mask Fitter            and have found that it <a href="https://dentistry.llu.edu/about/school-news/llu-school-dentistry-and-bellus3d-collaborate-mask-solutions-during-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">enhances the peripheral seal of a mask</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I wore a standard surgical mask with the fitter and a face shield to the grocery store yesterday and I felt <em>invulnerable</em>. Of course I sterilized the fitter and shield immediately afterwards, washed thoroughly, and tossed my clothes into the wash. My shoes are still on the steps outside. I know, I’m paranoid, but it’s not a lot of effort and I really don’t want to get or spread Covid-19!</p>
<p>I highly recommend these fitters. Wearing one protects me as well as it protects others.</p>
<p>OK this is the last time I’ll post about masks. I think I’ve covered the subject pretty thoroughly, and by now you know how I feel about them. If everyone wears a simple mask we can go back to life as usual <a href="https://www.axios.com/cdc-director-masking-coronavirus-dba00f19-4167-43a0-b021-9a9e66974517.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">in as little as a month</a>. Why wouldn’t you wear one?</p>
<p>And if it’s extra protection you’re after, put the Belus3D app on your iPhone X or later and make yourself a mask fitter!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>It’s Science, Buddy</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/07/science/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 11:27:21 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/07/science/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I keep finding articles describing why masks are important. This is from more than two months ago but it’s more important than ever.</p>
<p>Why simple cloth masks work best, from the Journal of <a href="https://aaqr.org/articles/aaqr-20-04-le-0154" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Aerosol and Air Quality Research</a><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<blockquote>
<p>By donning a homemade mask made of any 2-ply or more dense fabric, [Americans] would be able shrink their inhalation/exhalation radius immensely and  help stem the current outbreaks that are ravaging their country. In  addition, cloth masks can be tailor made to fit snugly and close the  gaping holes created by poorly fitting surgical masks. Furthermore, a  cloth mask can be easily decontaminated as it can be washed with  over-the-counter disinfectants, heated in an oven or treated by steam  sterilization above 70°C for longer than 5 mins, all proven methods to  effectively inactivate the SARS-CoV-2 virus (Chin <em>et al.</em>,  2020). Surgical masks are designed for single-use and can be  decontaminated by any of the above methods, including dry-heating in an  electric rice cooker (Lin <em>et al.</em>, 2017). However, the potential deformation and degraded effectiveness of the mask’s polymer layer after repeated treatments should be further evaluated. With that, the surgical masks are then thrown away and added to the mounting global  plastic pollution problem. Thus, the environmental cost of discarded  surgical masks is already being outlined and with the persistence of the COVID-19 pandemic and the slow, cautious transition back to normal,  this cost will grow unabated unless <strong>alternative mask usage is widely  promoted</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Still many of the people I see on the street are not wearing masks of any kind. And most of those who do are wearing poorly-fitted disposable surgical masks. Exactly the kind of mask this article is arguing against.</p>
<p>Since people seem unwilling to do anything to protect others, I’m going to have to take matters into my own hands by fully protecting myself whenever I go out using my own home-made PPE. Kind of like Jude Law in “<em>Contagion</em>” minus the oxygen tank.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/judelaw.jpg" title="Jude Law in his home-made PPE from the movie Contagion" data-thumbnail="/images/judelaw.jpg" data-sub-html="<h2>Jude Law in “Contagion</h2><p>Jude Law in his home-made PPE from the movie Contagion</p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Jude Law in “Contagion</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>I’m still waiting for my <a href="https://leo.fm/2020/06/improved/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">3D printed mask fitter</a> to come from Cadmus Dental. When it arrives I believe I’ll be able to sew mask squares composed of two layers of cotton with chiffon or silk in between that will provide almost perfect protection and still remain highly breathable. I also have a yard of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B087PJDPCR/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">meltblown polypropylene fabric</a> to try out.  Washing depletes the static charge on the chiffon, silk, or poly but virgourous ironing restores it. I iron all my masks after washing to further disinfect them. Plus putting on a freshly ironed mask is quite nice.</p>
<p>Wearing these masks with a face shield and coupled with apppropriate social distancing and hygiene I might be able to dodge this thing.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/leoprotected.png" title=" Leo wearing ball cap, homemade face mask, and face sheild. " data-thumbnail="/images/leoprotected.png" data-sub-html="<h2>My personal protection equipment</h2><p> Leo wearing ball cap, homemade face mask, and face sheild. </p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">My personal protection equipment</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>Our failed President said yesterday that <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/07/05/politics/donald-trump-july-4-coronavirus/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">99% of Covid cases are harmless</a>. That’s a lie. It is true that the mortality rate may be as low as 1% globally (still that’s 129,000 people in the US alone as of today), but according to the <a href="https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/situation-reports/20200416-sitrep-87-covid-19.pdf?sfvrsn=9523115a_2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">World Health Organization</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>While the majority of patients with COVID-19 have mild or moderated illness, it is estimated that 20% of affected patients will need oxygen.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Seems serious to me. And we’re only starting to learn of the long-term damage caused by even mild cases.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>Buy or make cloth masks people, and wear them whenever you’re out of the house. It’s the only way through this.</p>
<div class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>Hsiao, T.C., Chuang, H.C., Griffith, S.M., Chen, S.J. and Young, L.H.  (2020). COVID-19: An Aerosol&rsquo;s Point of View from Expiration to  Transmission to Viral-mechanism. <em>Aerosol Air Qual. Res.</em> 20:905-910. <a href="https://doi.org/10.4209/aaqr.2020.04.0154" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://doi.org/10.4209/aaqr.2020.04.0154</a>&#160;<a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>Calculating mortality and risks during a pandemic is hard. But the New York Times  has a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/05/us/politics/trump-coronavirus-factcheck.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">good article on the subject</a>. And the stories about healthy young people suffuring horrific consequences and even death are <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/nick-cordero-dead-bullets-broadway-waitress-actor-was-41-1301841" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">very scary</a>.&#160;<a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</div>]]></description></item></channel></rss>