<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>comments mastodon fediverse - Tag - leo.fm</title><link>https://leo.fm/tags/comments-mastodon-fediverse/</link><description>comments mastodon fediverse - Tag - leo.fm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</managingEditor><webMaster>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright 2022 Leo Laporte, all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo.fm/tags/comments-mastodon-fediverse/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A New Commenting System</title><link>https://leo.fm/2022/02/comments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2022/02/comments/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been using a third-party commenting system here, <a href="https://commento.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Commento</a>. But I think it&rsquo;s time to make a change.</p>
<p>Commento is well supported by my blog engine, Hugo. It&rsquo;s relatively inexpensive with a good set of features, but&hellip;. this is such a low volume blog that I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s worth the $5/month for Commento. That&rsquo;s no reflection on it - it&rsquo;s a nice system. But I like the idea of the Fediverse and I&rsquo;d like to support the Mastodon instance I run, <a href="https://twit.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">twit.social</a>.</p>
<p>It turns out it&rsquo;s pretty easy to use Mastodon comments with Hugo. I found a great <a href="https://carlschwan.eu/2020/12/29/adding-comments-to-your-static-blog-with-mastodon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">post by Carl Schwan</a> that included the code to insert in my theme. A simple copy and paste and - wow!- it worked! I modified the default header to include a link to twit.social. The only trick is to quickly edit the post metadata to point to the toot announcing the post. So it&rsquo;s not automatic, but it&rsquo;s not hard either. I&rsquo;m hoping that this will facilitate conversation on posts here, and, not incidentally, drive some traffic on Mastodon.</p>
<p>Thanks, Carl. To try it out - press &ldquo;Reply&rdquo; below and it will open a Mastodon form in your browser. Your comment will appear here and on your Mastodon account. If you don&rsquo;t have a Mastodon account, join us at <a href="https://twit.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">twit.social</a>. We&rsquo;d love to have you!</p>
<p>UPDAYE: Well for some reason that&rsquo;s not working at all. Sigh. I&rsquo;ll keep banging on it. I love the idea of creating a conversation about posts on Mastodon, especially since I&rsquo;m already running my own instance. Ironically one of the replies to this post was a complaint about my facetious cookie banner. Without Commento.io there are no cookies, so I&rsquo;m turning that off too.</p>
<p>Finally, I had it half working using Carl&rsquo;s code, but I did need to get some Javascript, purify.min.js, accesible. Carl uses it to sanitize HTML in comments. I stuck that dang code everywhere, but finally put it in /static/assets/js/ and lo and behold, it works! I still have a lot to learn about Hugo. Per Carl, I am using his &ldquo;Load Comments&rdquo; button to keep from hammering the Mastodon server. So have at it!</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>