<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>1st amendment - Tag - leo.fm</title><link>https://leo.fm/tags/1st-amendment/</link><description>1st amendment - Tag - leo.fm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</managingEditor><webMaster>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright 2022 Leo Laporte, all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 08:43:04 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo.fm/tags/1st-amendment/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The First Amendment</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/06/firstamendment/</link><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jun 2020 08:43:04 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/06/firstamendment/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I, too, believe in the rule of law, Mr. President.</p>
<h3 id="the-first-amendment-of-the-constitution-of-the-united-states-of-america">The First Amendment of The Constitution of The United States of America</h3>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/First_Amendment_to_the_United_States_Constitution" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer"></a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Congress shall make no law respecting an establishment of religion, or prohibiting the free exercise thereof; or abridging the freedom of speech, or of the press; or <strong>the right of the people peaceably to assemble, and to petition the Government for a redress of grievances.</strong></p>
</blockquote>
<p>And this quote today from Trump&rsquo;s first Secretary of Defense, James Mattis:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>I have watched this week’s unfolding events, angry and appalled, The words &ldquo;Equal Justice Under Law&rdquo; are carved in the pediment of the United States Supreme Court. This is precisely what protesters are rightly demanding. It is a wholesome and unifying demand—one that all of us should be able to get behind. We must not be distracted by a small number of lawbreakers. The protests are defined by tens of thousands of people of conscience who are insisting that we live up to our values—our values as people and our values as a nation. We must reject and hold accountable those in office who would make a mockery of our Constitution.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Read the full statement <a href="https://www.theatlantic.com/politics/archive/2020/06/james-mattis-denounces-trump-protests-militarization/612640/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">here</a>.</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>