<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>bio - Tag - leo.fm</title><link>https://leo.fm/tags/bio/</link><description>bio - Tag - leo.fm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</managingEditor><webMaster>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright 2022 Leo Laporte, all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:53:33 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo.fm/tags/bio/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Official Biography</title><link>https://leo.fm/bio/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:53:33 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/bio/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/headshot.jpg" title=" Official Headshot " data-thumbnail="/images/headshot.jpg" data-sub-html="<h2>Official Headshot -- Photo credit: [Chris Marquardt](https://tfttf.com)</h2><p> Official Headshot </p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Official Headshot -- Photo credit: [Chris Marquardt](https://tfttf.com)</figcaption>
    </figure>
Leo Laporte has worked as an author, speaker, and broadcaster in New Haven, Monterey, San Jose, San Francisco, and Los Angeles, most recently focusing on technology coverage for radio, television, and the Internet.</p>
<h3>Past</h3>Leo has written software for CP/M, Macintosh, and PC compatible computers including the popular open source programs, QDial and MacArc for the Macintosh. From 1985 to 1988, he operated one of the first Macintosh-only computer bulletin board systems, MacQueue
<p>He was the co-author, with former ABC Technology Correspondent Gina Smith, of &ldquo;<em>101 Computer Answers You Need to Know</em>,&rdquo; a computer book for beginners published in 1995 by Ziff-Davis Press. He has written about computer hardware and software for Byte, MacUser, and InfoWorld magazines, and he has contributed chapters to &ldquo;<em>Dvorak&rsquo;s Guide to PC Telecommunications&rdquo;</em> and &ldquo;<em>Dvorak&rsquo;s Inside Track to the Mac</em>,&rdquo; both published by Osborne/McGraw Hill. He has written four bestselling &ldquo;<em>Technology Almanacs</em>.&rdquo; &ldquo;<em>Leo Laporte&rsquo;s 2003 Technology Almanac&rdquo;</em> was Pearson Publishing&rsquo;s Book of the Year in 2003.</p>
<p>In 2000-2001, Leo was a Contributing Editor at Access Magazine, a Sunday newspaper magazine supplement with an estimated readership of 13 million in 80 markets nationwide.</p>
<p>In January, 1991 he created and co-hosted <em>Dvorak On Computers</em>, the most listened to high tech talk radio show in the nation, syndicated on over 60 stations and around the world on the Armed Forces Radio Network. Laporte also hosted <em>Laporte on Computers</em> on KSFO and KGO Radio in San Francisco.</p>
<p>On television, Leo was host of <em>Internet!</em> a weekly half-hour show airing on PBS in 215 cities nationwide. He reported on new media for <em>Today&rsquo;s First Edition</em>, on PBS, and did daily product reviews and demos on <em>New Media News</em>, broadcast nationally on Jones Computer Network and ME/U, and regionally on San Francisco&rsquo;s Bay TV.</p>
<p>He was a Managing Editor at Ziff-Davis Television, where he wrote and co-hosted <em>The Personal Computing Show,</em> a half-hour weekly television show for beginning computer users that aired on CNBC. He created and was a daily contributor to <em>The Site</em>, an hour-long technology newsmagazine that aired nightly on MSNBC, CNBC International, and NBC Superchannel in Europe and Asia. Leo won an Emmy in 1997 for his work on The Site. He also hosted two shows on TechTV (formerly ZDTV), a 24-hour cable channel dedicated to computers and the Internet. <em>Call for Help</em> and <em>The Screen Savers</em> aired live every weekday from 1998 to 2004.</p>
<p>After <em>Call for Help</em> was cancelled in the US, Leo began producing the show in Toronto for Rogers Communications. The show aired in Canada on G4TechTV, and Australia on the HOW-TO Channel. Rogers moved production to Vancouver in 2007 and renamed it <em>The Lab with Leo Laporte</em>. The show ended its ten-year run in May, 2008.</p>
<h3>Present</h3>Currently Leo hosts <em>The Tech Guy Show</em> a national radio technology talk show every Saturday and Sunday from 2-5p Eastern on over 200 stations on the Premiere Networks including KFI, Los Angeles and KGO, San Francisco.
<p>Founded in April, 2005, his TWiT Netcast Network produces some of the most popular podcasts in the world heard by more than 6 million listeners and viewers each month including shows like <em>this WEEK in TECH</em>, <em>Security Now!</em>, <em>Windows Weekly</em>, <em>MacBreak Weekly</em>, <em>This Week in Google</em>,  and the Webby Award winning, <em>Triangulation.</em></p>
<p>In May, 2008, Leo launched a live streaming video version of TWiT called <a href="http://live.twit.tv">TWiT Live</a> with 25 hours of original programming each week. 2.6 million people watched TWiT Live in its first month and the numbers continue to grow. TWiT broadcasts daily from a dedicated live-streaming video studio in Petaluma, California. Leo lives with his wife and TWiT CEO, Lisa Laporte, in Petaluma.</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>To request Leo as a speaker or for an interview on your show, email <a href="mailto:requests@twit.tv"><a href="mailto:requests@twit.tv">requests@twit.tv</a></a>. For information about pitching Leo on your product visit our <a href="/pr/" rel="">PR page</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Leo_Laporte">Wikipedia </a>Profile (usually mostly accurate)</p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></description></item><item><title/><link>https://leo.fm/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/about/</guid><description><![CDATA[<h1 id="-hello-my-name-is-leo-laporte">🙏 Hello. My name is Leo Laporte.</h1>
<p>I am a US-based journalist specializing in technology coverage on radio, TV, and the Internet.</p>
<p>This site (leo.fm) is a place I store quick posts. I guess it&rsquo;s the closest thing I have to a blog these days. Well done finding it.</p>
<p>leo.fm is a static site generated from markdown files using <a href="https://gohugo.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Hugo</a>. The site template is <a href="https://themes.gohugo.io/loveit/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">LoveIt</a>. The server is running Debian and nginx out of the TWiT studios. I mirror it at Github (<a href="https://leolaporte.github.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">leolaporte.github.io</a> - that&rsquo;s one of the many benefits of a static site!</p>
<p>I have several other web sites you might be more interested in:</p>
<ul>
<li>
<p>You&rsquo;ll find notes and audio from my nationally syndicated radio talk show at <a href="https://techguylabs.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">The Tech Guy Labs</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I also host and produce multiple technology-focused podcasts at <a href="https://twit.tv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">TWiT</a>. You can download them all on the TWiT.tv website or subscribe on <a href="https://podcasts.apple.com/us/podcast/all-twit-shows-mp3/id269795738" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">iTunes</a>. Watch us produce the shows live at <a href="https://twit.tv/live" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">TWiT Live</a> or listen in at <a href="https://twit.am/listen" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">TWiT.am</a>. Listen live any time on your voice assisted devices by saying &ldquo;Hey [device name here], listen to TWiT Live.&rdquo;</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Chat with me and members of the TWiT community in our community-run IRC channel #twitlive at <a href="http://irc.twit.tv/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">irc.twit.tv</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Our official forums are at <a href="https://www.twit.community" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">TWiT.community</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://twit.tv/clubtwit" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Club TWiT</a> members ($7/month) can chat with me and the team on our private Discord server, and get ad-free versions of all our shows, and a special TWiT+ podcast feed.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I don&rsquo;t use Facebook or Twitter, preferring instead to use a federated social network called Mastodon. Our official TWiT Mastodon instance is at <a href="https://twit.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">TWiT.social</a> and I am <a href="https://twit.social/@leo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">leo@twit.social</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For secure messages to me (or anyone) don&rsquo;t use email. My secure <a href="https://signal.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Signal</a> messaging ID is 302-536-8948.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>I&rsquo;m an avid amateur photographer and post my best photos (such as they are) at <a href="https://www.leo.camera" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">www.leo.camera</a> and <a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/leoville/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Flickr</a>. I&rsquo;m @ChiefTWiT on <a href="https://glass.photo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">glass.photo</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>For information about advertising visit <a href="https://leo.fm/advertise" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">leo.fm/advertise</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>PR professionals, please visit <a href="https://leo.fm/pr" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">leo.fm/pr</a> before pitching me.</p>
</li>
</ul>
<p>I use <a href="https://gnupg.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">GNU Privacy Guard (gpg)</a> or S/MIME signing for email whenever possible. Mail from me will be signed with my PGP key with the short ID 4567B47C or GlobalSign S/MIME certificate ID 582BC167. Email addresses are easily spoofed, but signatures can generally be trusted. If you receive an email from me that is not signed, reply requesting a signed version before trusting it.</p>
<p>If you&rsquo;d like to encrypt your email to me, or verify a message from me, use my public PGP key: <a href="https://leo.ist/Leo%20Laporte%202018-2022%20%284567B47C%29%20%E2%80%93%20Public.asc" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Leo Laporte 2018-2022 (4567B47C)</a>. I create new keys every few years so be sure to use this key and not older versions. (This key is dated June 8, 2018 and identified as <a href="mailto:leo@leoville.com">leo@leoville.com</a>). It&rsquo;s probably easier (and even more secure) to use <a href="https://signal.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Signal</a> messenger (302-536-8948). My phone rejects calls from unknown numbers, but you can leave a text or voice message.</p>
<p>My full bio is posted at <a href="https://leo.fm/bio" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">leo.fm/bio</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Contact Info:</strong></p>
<p><strong>Email:</strong> <a href="mailto:info@leo.fm">info@leo.fm</a></p>
<p><strong>Voice mail/SMS/Signal:</strong> +1 302-536-8948</p>
<p><strong>Snail mail:</strong> Leo Laporte, 1351 Redwood Way, Ste. B, Petaluma, CA 94954</p>
<hr>
<h3 id="answers-to-questions-people-frequently-ask-me">Answers to questions people frequently ask me:</h3>
<p><strong>What&rsquo;s the best way to stay secure online?</strong></p>
<p>Start by using a password manager.</p>
<p>We all need to use passwords all the time. The problem with passwords is that good ones are hard to remember. So people often use weak (but memorable passwords) and reuse them on site after site. A better way is to use a program that generates long, really random (hence unmemorable) passwords and keeps track of them so you don’t have to. That’s a password manager. If you only use your Mac and an iPhone, Apple can do this for you with the keychain. Your browser can also keep track of your passwords, if somewhat insecurely.</p>
<p><a href="https://bitwarden.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">BitWarden</a> is open-source, inexpensive, and very secure. It generates long, strong passwords and remembers them for you. <a href="https://lastpass.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Lastpass</a> and <a href="https://1password.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">1Password</a> are also excellent and work the same way.</p>
<p>Two more important tips:</p>
<ul>
<li>If you use Gmail, follow Google’s security advice at <a href="https://google.com/security">https://google.com/security</a> – make sure to add a recovery phone number and email.</li>
<li>Turn-on two factor authentication wherever you can.</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>What programming language should I learn?</strong></p>
<p>If you merely want to get a job as quickly as possible go to one of the many coding camps and study Javascript. If you want to learn the art of programming. I recommend starting right with the free textbook <a href="https://htdp.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">How To Design Programs</a>. HtDP uses the free <a href="https://racket-lang.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">DrRacket</a> language and IDE. Racket is a lisp, but as they use it in the book it’s a much simplified teaching language. It’s intended to get out of the way so you can learn coding concepts without having to struggle with language syntax.</p>
<p>There’s a well-done free pair of online courses from the University of British Columbia that teaches HtDP at <a href="https://www.edx.org/course/how-to-code-simple-data" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">edX.org</a>. I highly recommend them (I’ve done them myself.)</p>
<p>Once you&rsquo;ve learned how to think about programs you can study any other language and you&rsquo;ll be a better programmer for it.</p>
<p><strong>Can I promote X with you?</strong></p>
<p>I appreciate your sending along information about your product, service, web site, brilliant idea, or podcast proposal. I wish you all the best. I will read it and store it away for future reference. I don’t meet with vendors, so please don’t ask. TWiT.tv isn’t looking for any more podcasts either, but good luck with your show!</p>
<p><strong>How do I buy ads on your shows?</strong></p>
<p>Advertising Sales for TWiT is handled through Lisa Laporte, <a href="mailto:lisa@twit.tv">lisa@twit.tv</a>. Our minimum buy is $25,000. Thanks so much for your support!!</p>
<p><strong>Please help me!</strong></p>
<p>Thanks so much for writing. Unfortunately due to the volume of mail I get I just don’t have the ability to answer individual questions. I’ll keep your question in mind for use on the podcasts or radio show, though. You might search my radio show web site for an answer. I’ve also found that searching Google can be helpful. If you’d like to ask your question on my syndicated radio show call 1-88-88-ASK LEO from 11a-2p Pacific weekends. I appreciate hearing from you. I hope you understand why I can’t be of much help.</p>
]]></description></item></channel></rss>