<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>blog - Category - leo.fm</title><link>https://leo.fm/categories/blog/</link><description>blog - Category - leo.fm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</managingEditor><webMaster>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright 2022 Leo Laporte, all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 08:47:05 -0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo.fm/categories/blog/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Easy Hugo</title><link>https://leo.fm/2022/05/easy-hugo/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 08:47:05 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2022/05/easy-hugo/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>If you can read this I&rsquo;m too close.</p>
<p>Close to nirvana that is! I&rsquo;m posting this using emacs and an emacs extension called <a href="https://github.com/masasam/emacs-easy-hugo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">easy-hugo</a>. I&rsquo;m writing this in Markdown mode, but it also supports org-mode, HTML, AsciiDoc, and a number of other major modes. Works with S3, github, Google cloud storage, etc.</p>
<p>Honestly this wouldn&rsquo;t be a big deal, but I&rsquo;m really trying to find ways to post more often. And that means reducing the friction of writing as much as possible. Emacs is always open on any computer I&rsquo;m using. Which now means&hellip; so is my blog.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Now</title><link>https://leo.fm/now/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 May 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/now/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>This is my <a href="https://nownownow.com/about" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">now page</a>. I&rsquo;ll check in from time to time to tell folks what I&rsquo;m doing. Now.</p>
<h3 id="working-on-learning-lisp">Working on learning Lisp</h3>
<p>Wed 04 May 2022 11:20:05 PM PDT</p>
<p>I got pretty good at Racket (a version of  Scheme) by reading <a href="https://htdp.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">How to Design Programs</a> and taking a related online class from Gregor Kilczales from the University of British Columbia on <a href="https://learning.edx.org/course/course-v1:UBCx&#43;HtC1x&#43;2T2017/home" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">EDX</a>. Good enough to earn 37 out of 50 stars in the 2021 Advent of Code (although I stopped more because I ran out of interest than I ran out of Scheme).. My solutions are on <a href="https://github.com/leolaporte/AOC/tree/main/AOC21" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Github</a>. I&rsquo;m really proud of them.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been programming for fun for a long time - more than 40 years. I wrote a daemon dialer for my Mac BBS in 68000 assembler in 1986. I know it was 1986 because I remember watching the Space Shuttle Challenger blow up while I was doing it.</p>
<p>A few years ago I decided to start over and learn how to program right. That&rsquo;s when I started HtDP and Racket. But everyone agrees the king of languages is Lisp. <a href="https://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Eric_S._Raymond" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">esr</a> says:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Lisp is worth learning for the profound enlightenment experience you will have when you finally get it; that experience will make you a better programmer for the rest of your days, even if you never actually use Lisp itself a lot.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So now I&rsquo;m working on that. I like Lisp because it&rsquo;s exactly as old as I am and it hasn&rsquo;t changed in 40 years. Unlike me.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been using the following books to learn:</p>
<ol>
<li><a href="https://www.cs.cmu.edu/~dst/LispBook/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Common Lisp, A Gentle Introduction to Symbolic Computing by David Touretzky</a></li>
<li><a href="https://gigamonkeys.com/book/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Practical Common Lisp by Peter Siebel</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/acl.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">ANSI Common Lisp by Paul Graham</a></li>
<li><a href="http://www.paulgraham.com/onlisp.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">On Lisp by Paul Graham</a></li>
</ol>
<p>I recommend all four in that order. I&rsquo;m hoping to do this year&rsquo;s Advent of Code in Lisp. And get all 50 stars, too.</p>
<h3 id="learning-emacs">Learning Emacs</h3>
<p>Wed 04 May 2022 11:45:11 PM PDT</p>
<p>Part of learning Lisp is learning Emacs. They go hand-in-hand. I don&rsquo;t think I can really become adept at it in my remaining 18 years but it&rsquo;s fun to try. I&rsquo;m also trying to learn its org-mode for journaling, note-taking, and list making. It&rsquo;s pretty handy.</p>
<h3 id="planning-a-cruise-to-alaska">Planning a cruise to Alaska</h3>
<p>Wed 04 May 2022 11:20:39 PM PDT</p>
<p>Sometimes I think the best part of travelling is planning the trip. The expectation is thrilling. I&rsquo;m using <a href="https://notion.so" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Notion</a> to plan it out. Lisa and I are going with Paul Thurrott (my Windows Weekly co-host) and his wife plus 100 or so TWiT listeners this July.</p>
<h3 id="coming-to-grips-with-aging">Coming to grips with aging</h3>
<p>Wed 04 May 2022 11:40:07 PM PDT</p>
<p>My mom turns 90 in January my dad next July. They&rsquo;re both sharp and healthy but they&rsquo;re slowing down and I know I won&rsquo;t have many more years with them. I&rsquo;m 65. Retirement age.</p>
<p>According to the <a href="https://www.livingto100.com/calculator/age" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Life Expetancy Calculator</a> I have about 18 years left. That&rsquo;s it. I worry about being a burden to my family in my later years, even though my parents aren&rsquo;t yet. I&rsquo;ve read Atul Gawande&rsquo;s excellent (and sad) <a href="http://atulgawande.com/book/being-mortal/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Being Mortal</a> and it scares me. I&rsquo;m an atheist so I don&rsquo;t have any hopes of an afterlife. Although, as I get nearer to the end I notice that Nick Bostrom&rsquo;s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Simulation_hypothesis" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">simulation hypothesis</a> gets more appealing. Even more believable.</p>
<p>I also wonder if I shouldn&rsquo;t retire soon so I can enjoy my remaining years. (I have about the same amount of time left as I&rsquo;ve been doing TWiT. That seems like a very short time.) I want to travel and my work schedule makes it hard to go on the longer trips I dream about, especially an around the world cruise. I have enough money saved to retire fairly comfortably, even go on that cruise, but I still am the primary support for several family members and I am afraid of leaving them in the lurch. And then I wonder if <em>not</em> working will drive me nuts. I think it&rsquo;s likely I&rsquo;ll begin to work less and less over the next few years and by the time I&rsquo;m 70 just do one, audio-only, podcast a week until my voice or my brains give out.</p>
<h3 id="reading">Reading</h3>
<p>I&rsquo;m on book four of the very fun <a href="https://www.audible.com/series/Bobiverse-Audiobooks/B01M1RDL6W" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Bobiverse series</a> from Dennis E. Taylor. Ray Porter reads it for Audible and he&rsquo;s just perfect, as he was narrating the excellent Project Hail Mary by Andy Weir. Porter&rsquo;s a master of modern wise-ass delivery. (Wed 04 May 2022 11:51:48 PM PDT)</p>
<p>Also attempting David Graeber&rsquo;s The Dawn of Everything (archeology and world pre-history) and I&rsquo;m mired in the slog - book six - of the Wheel of Time. I may not finish that one. I only have 18 years left, remember. (Wed 04 May 2022 11:54:56 PM PDT)</p>
<h3 id="tv">TV</h3>
<p>I watch way too much TV. Several hours a night with Lisa. Loved Succession on HBO and Slow Horses on AppleTV+ but I&rsquo;m having a hard time finding anything I love as much these days. Just started Outer Range on Amazon Prime - it&rsquo;s kind of like Yosemite meets Stranger Things and I&rsquo;m not sure whether I like it yet. Also started Under the Banner of Heaven on Hulu. It&rsquo;s creepy and the partiarchal Mormonism in it hits a little too painfully close to home in our newly Christian Nationalistic America. (Thu 05 May 2022 12:00:15 AM PDT)</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Mission Accomplished</title><link>https://leo.fm/2022/02/isitover/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Feb 2022 08:51:59 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2022/02/isitover/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I created this site in the midst of a pandemic. Now two years later, it&rsquo;s over. Right?</p>
<p>Today mask mandates are lifted in our county and, despite <a href="https://www.nbcnews.com/health/health-news/mask-mandates-can-people-stop-wearing-masks-covid-rcna14587" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">cowardly quibbling from the CDC</a>, most of the US. It seems the pandemic ends with a whimper, not a bang. Sunday&rsquo;s mostly-maskless Superbowl was the party we&rsquo;ve all been waiting for. And, yet, I&rsquo;m not exactly ready to celebrate. Personally, I&rsquo;m planning to tiptoe back, mask at the ready. I&rsquo;d love to make a pyre in the backyard to burn them all, but what if there&rsquo;s a new virulent variant? We still have Π Ρ Σ Τ Υ Φ Χ Ψ and Ω if we need them.</p>
<p>But, for now, I&rsquo;m willing to say Mission Accomplished. Good job everyone. Let&rsquo;s say a prayer for the nearly one million dead in the US, nearly six million worldwide (a chilling number) and get back to living. Save the remaining ivermectin for the horses, shall we?</p>
<p>Oh, and get your goldurn vaccine, will ya? For me? For all of us!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Like Father, Like Son</title><link>https://leo.fm/2022/02/likefatherlikeson/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Feb 2022 19:29:30 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2022/02/likefatherlikeson/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday my son showed up at the studio. I took the opportunity to interview him!</p>
<p>Henry (or Hank as he&rsquo;s known now) has become a <a href="https://www.tiktok.com/@salt_hank?lang=en" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">big-time Tik Tok chef</a> with 1.8 million followers and nearly 30 million likes. Check out his videos and, as soon as he gets more, you can also buy his salt at <a href="https://salthank.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">salthank.com</a>.</p>
<p>We tried to reproduce a photo from 27-years-ago at KSFO.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/fathersandsons.png" title="Fathers and Sons 27 Years Apart" data-thumbnail="/images/fathersandsons.png" data-sub-html="<h2>Fathers and Sons 27-years apart</h2><p>Fathers and Sons 27 Years Apart</p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Fathers and Sons 27-years apart</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>Thanks to RailEuropeGroups from Club TWiT for the Photoshop! And here&rsquo;s the clip from Sunday&rsquo;s show.</p>
<iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/IgBcgt17iLU?start=3937" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
<p>I guess I&rsquo;m kind of a proud father!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>A New Commenting System</title><link>https://leo.fm/2022/02/comments/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2022/02/comments/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;ve been using a third-party commenting system here, <a href="https://commento.io" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Commento</a>. But I think it&rsquo;s time to make a change.</p>
<p>Commento is well supported by my blog engine, Hugo. It&rsquo;s relatively inexpensive with a good set of features, but&hellip;. this is such a low volume blog that I don&rsquo;t think it&rsquo;s worth the $5/month for Commento. That&rsquo;s no reflection on it - it&rsquo;s a nice system. But I like the idea of the Fediverse and I&rsquo;d like to support the Mastodon instance I run, <a href="https://twit.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">twit.social</a>.</p>
<p>It turns out it&rsquo;s pretty easy to use Mastodon comments with Hugo. I found a great <a href="https://carlschwan.eu/2020/12/29/adding-comments-to-your-static-blog-with-mastodon/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">post by Carl Schwan</a> that included the code to insert in my theme. A simple copy and paste and - wow!- it worked! I modified the default header to include a link to twit.social. The only trick is to quickly edit the post metadata to point to the toot announcing the post. So it&rsquo;s not automatic, but it&rsquo;s not hard either. I&rsquo;m hoping that this will facilitate conversation on posts here, and, not incidentally, drive some traffic on Mastodon.</p>
<p>Thanks, Carl. To try it out - press &ldquo;Reply&rdquo; below and it will open a Mastodon form in your browser. Your comment will appear here and on your Mastodon account. If you don&rsquo;t have a Mastodon account, join us at <a href="https://twit.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">twit.social</a>. We&rsquo;d love to have you!</p>
<p>UPDAYE: Well for some reason that&rsquo;s not working at all. Sigh. I&rsquo;ll keep banging on it. I love the idea of creating a conversation about posts on Mastodon, especially since I&rsquo;m already running my own instance. Ironically one of the replies to this post was a complaint about my facetious cookie banner. Without Commento.io there are no cookies, so I&rsquo;m turning that off too.</p>
<p>Finally, I had it half working using Carl&rsquo;s code, but I did need to get some Javascript, purify.min.js, accesible. Carl uses it to sanitize HTML in comments. I stuck that dang code everywhere, but finally put it in /static/assets/js/ and lo and behold, it works! I still have a lot to learn about Hugo. Per Carl, I am using his &ldquo;Load Comments&rdquo; button to keep from hammering the Mastodon server. So have at it!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Am I Crazy?</title><link>https://leo.fm/2021/03/amiafool/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 08:43:48 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2021/03/amiafool/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I pulled the trigger on a Monster Gaming Machine. I know it&rsquo;s crazy, but boys just want to have fun.</p>
<p>See I have a three-year-old iMac Pro, but it&rsquo;s getting flaky and I&rsquo;ve been eyeing my wife&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/dell-ultrasharp-49-curved-monitor-u4919dw/apd/210-arnw/monitors-monitor-accessories" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">49&quot; monitor</a> for months.</p>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/fool/widescreen.jpeg" title="Lisa&rsquo;s BAM" data-thumbnail="/images/fool/widescreen.jpeg" data-sub-html="<h2>Dell 49-inch Curved Monitor</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Dell 49-inch Curved Monitor</figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>Apple&rsquo;s never going to do something like that! And how long before they ship something powerful that can work with an external monitor: A high-end mac Mini or a new mini-Mac Pro?</p>
<p>I finally lost my patience and pulled the trigger on something <a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/work/shop/desktops-all-in-one-pcs/alienware-aurora-ryzen-edition-r10-gaming-desktop/spd/alienware-aurora-r10-desktop/wdryzr10v20hsb" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">completely different</a>.</p>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/fool/aurora.jpeg" title="Alienware Aurora R10" data-thumbnail="/images/fool/aurora.jpeg" data-sub-html="<h2>Alienware Aurora Ryzen Edition R10</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Alienware Aurora Ryzen Edition R10</figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>Maxed out with a Ryzen 7 5800X, nVidia GTX 3080, 128GB RAM, and dual 2TB drives (1 m.2, 1 spinning).</p>
<p>I know I could save money and probably get something better by building my own or going to a custom gaming PC maker, but these components are hard to get and I figure Dell can get them faster than anyone else. Even so this baby doesn&rsquo;t ship &rsquo;til May.</p>
<p>And as long as I&rsquo;m going for a power rig, I might as well go all out with a <a href="https://www.dell.com/en-us/shop/new-alienware-55-oled-gaming-monitor-aw5520qf/apd/210-auds/monitors-monitor-accessories" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">monster monitor</a>, right?</p>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/fool/55incher.jpeg" title="Alienware 55-inch OLED Gaming Monitor" data-thumbnail="/images/fool/55incher.jpeg" data-sub-html="<h2>Alienware 55-inch OLED Gaming Monitor</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Alienware 55-inch OLED Gaming Monitor</figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>A 55-inch OLED monitor that&rsquo;s absurdly expensive. (It&rsquo;s basically a hi-res TV but it costs a lot more.)</p>
<p>I rationalize this crazy purchase because</p>
<ol>
<li>I believe in open source, and like Linux as much as I like macOS. Dell supports Linux pretty well. (No I don&rsquo;t plan on using Windows. Ick.)</li>
<li>I really need to get to know the new PC hardware. Specifically The AMD Ryzen and the new nVidia ray-tracing GPUs.</li>
<li>I can&rsquo;t get an Xbox Series X or Playstation 5 to save my life, but I really want to play something new.</li>
<li>and the real reason&hellip; <a href="https://www.valheimgame.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Valheim</a> (it runs on Linux!)</li>
</ol>
<p>I&rsquo;ve been saving up for something like this for some time. It&rsquo;s kind of the Ultimate Gaming Machine for 2021.</p>
<p>OK tell me I&rsquo;m a fool. I&rsquo;m ready to be roasted. Or you can come over and watch me play Valheim come May.</p>
<p>UPDATE: It has arrived. I&rsquo;ve been playing with it all day and it&rsquo;s so fast. Super happy with the purchase. Dual booting Windows 10 with Manjaro Linux and everything is working perfectly. I think I&rsquo;m in love.</p>]]></description></item><item><title>I Am Not Throwing Away THIS Shot</title><link>https://leo.fm/2021/03/gottheshot/</link><pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 17:15:57 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2021/03/gottheshot/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Yesterday I got the first shot of the Covid-19 vaccine!</p>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/vaccine.png" title="Waiting to get a Fauci Ouchie" data-thumbnail="/images/vaccine.png" data-sub-html="<h2>In the waiting room</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">In the waiting room</figcaption>
    </figure>
<p>When I arrived at Kaiser they threw me a curve. &ldquo;Would you like Moderna or Johnson &amp; Johnson?&rdquo; I chose Moderna for a variety of reasons, but mostly because I think the mRNA technology is very cool. The process was quick and nearly painless. Afterwards I hod to wait 15 minutes, just in case I had a bad reaction. I didn&rsquo;t. My arm hurts a bit today, but that&rsquo;s the extent of the side effects. I expect worse after the second shot, April 14.</p>
<p>Now we just have to get the rest of my friends and family vaccinated and life can kind of get back to normal!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>It's Right Against Wrong, Not Smart Against Dumb</title><link>https://leo.fm/2021/02/qanon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 09:01:27 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2021/02/qanon/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Just because someone believes in conspiracy theories, doesn&rsquo;t mean they&rsquo;re dumb.</p>
<p>From an article in <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/161266/qanon-classism-marjorie-taylor-greene" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">The New Republic</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The University of Minnesota’s Joanne Miller and Christina Farhart and Colorado State University’s Kyle Saunders conducted a survey examining support for conspiracy theories, including birtherism and 9/11 trutherism. In a result unsurprising to those who follow this research, they found that higher levels of political knowledge actually deepened the likelihood that conservatives with low trust in people and major institutions would endorse right-wing conspiracy theories. In a section reviewing previous research on the subject, the authors explained that political sophisticates “have the ability to make connections between abstract principles and more concrete attitudes and are therefore more fully able to notice the implications of specific attitudes for their worldviews.” “Because politically knowledgeable people care more about politics and hold stronger political attitudes,” they added, “they are especially likely to want to protect those attitudes.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The researchers conclude that &ldquo;people will believe what they want to believe in spite of available data and evidence.&rdquo;</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Tweet to Toot</title><link>https://leo.fm/2021/01/tweet2toot/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2021/01/tweet2toot/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I admit the timing is confusing. No I&rsquo;m not leaving Twitter because they blocked Trump. Duh.</p>
<p>It&rsquo;s just too toxic on Twitter. The continued trolling was hurting our team, our hosts, and our business, so we decided, as a team, to pack up and move out. I don&rsquo;t know about you, but I always found Twitter mildly disturbing. I won&rsquo;t miss it (any more than I miss Facebook).</p>
<p>We&rsquo;re not going dark, though. Not at all.</p>
<p>If you want to keep up on what&rsquo;s coming up on TWiT, subscribe to our free newsletter at <a href="https://twit.tv/newsletter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://twit.tv/newsletter</a>. The network also has an active <a href="https://facebook.com/twitnetwork" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Facebook</a> and <a href="https://instagram.com/twit.tv" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Instagram</a> presence. And, of course, many TWiTs are active on the <a href="https://www.twit.community" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">TWiT Forums</a>. We&rsquo;d love to see you there, too!</p>
<p>Instead of tweeting, I&rsquo;m tooting at <a href="https://twit.social/@leo" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">@leo@twit.social</a>. You can follow and message me there from any <a href="https://joinmastodon.org" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Mastodon instance</a> (that&rsquo;s one of the reasons I love Mastodon: it&rsquo;s <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Distributed_social_network" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">federated</a>). If you don&rsquo;t already have a Mastodon account, you&rsquo;re welcome to join me at <a href="https://twit.social" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">twit.social</a>. To eliminate spam and trolls, you do have to be manually approved - but I promise to do that within a day or two.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve also moved the old Twitter news links feed, @links_for_twit to <a href="https://twit.social/@twitnews" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">@twitnews@twit.social</a>. These are links to stories I&rsquo;m following for our shows. It&rsquo;s automatically generated from my <a href="https://pinboard.in/u:leolaporte" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Pinboard feed</a>.</p>
<p>Thanks for understanding. See you in the Fediverse!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Guilty as Charged</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/11/guilty/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2020 21:36:39 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/11/guilty/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I resemble that cartoon.</p>
<figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/blogging.jpg" title="Blogging vs. blog setups" data-thumbnail="/images/blogging.jpg" data-sub-html="<h2>via Rakhim https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined/19/</h2>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">via Rakhim <a href="https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined/19/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">https://rakhim.org/honestly-undefined/19/</a></figcaption>
    </figure>]]></description></item></channel></rss>