<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>politics - Tag - leo.fm</title><link>https://leo.fm/tags/politics/</link><description>politics - Tag - leo.fm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</managingEditor><webMaster>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright 2022 Leo Laporte, all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 09:01:27 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo.fm/tags/politics/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>It's Right Against Wrong, Not Smart Against Dumb</title><link>https://leo.fm/2021/02/qanon/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 09:01:27 -0800</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2021/02/qanon/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Just because someone believes in conspiracy theories, doesn&rsquo;t mean they&rsquo;re dumb.</p>
<p>From an article in <a href="https://newrepublic.com/article/161266/qanon-classism-marjorie-taylor-greene" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">The New Republic</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The University of Minnesota’s Joanne Miller and Christina Farhart and Colorado State University’s Kyle Saunders conducted a survey examining support for conspiracy theories, including birtherism and 9/11 trutherism. In a result unsurprising to those who follow this research, they found that higher levels of political knowledge actually deepened the likelihood that conservatives with low trust in people and major institutions would endorse right-wing conspiracy theories. In a section reviewing previous research on the subject, the authors explained that political sophisticates “have the ability to make connections between abstract principles and more concrete attitudes and are therefore more fully able to notice the implications of specific attitudes for their worldviews.” “Because politically knowledgeable people care more about politics and hold stronger political attitudes,” they added, “they are especially likely to want to protect those attitudes.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The researchers conclude that &ldquo;people will believe what they want to believe in spite of available data and evidence.&rdquo;</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Lest We Forget</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/07/lestweforget/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 08:23:25 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/07/lestweforget/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Just putting a bookmark here so I can refer people to this page when they say The Donald is a great president. Here&rsquo;s extensive proof otherwise.</p>
<p>From McSweeney&rsquo;s <a href="https://www.mcsweeneys.net/articles/the-complete-listing-so-far-atrocities-1-759" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Lest We Forget the Horrors: A Catalog of Trump’s Worst Cruelties, Collusions, Corruptions, and Crimes</a></p>
<p>No need to read the whole thing. Just start with the first five items. How did this clown get elected?</p>]]></description></item></channel></rss>