<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>masks - Tag - leo.fm</title><link>https://leo.fm/tags/masks/</link><description>masks - Tag - leo.fm</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</managingEditor><webMaster>leo@leo.fm (Leo Laporte)</webMaster><copyright>Copyright 2022 Leo Laporte, all rights reserved</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://leo.fm/tags/masks/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>A Perfect Fit</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/07/maskfitters/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/07/maskfitters/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>My 3D printed custom mask fitters have arrived and they’re swell!</p>
<p>Remember my post from last month about <a href="https://leo.fm/2020/06/improved/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">creating a mask fitter using Belus3D</a>?</p>
<p>Well they’re arrived and I have to say they really work. The idea is that the fitter, contoured perfectly to your face thanks to the software generated model, seals the mask material around your mouth and nose so that no air escapes around the edges. You are  breathing only through the mask.</p>
<p>I’ve ordered about eight of them from three different companies. All three specialize in printing dental implants. I used the three featured on the <a href="https://bellus3d.com/solutions/mask-fitter-order" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Belus3D ordering page</a>.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.cadmusdental.com/cadmus-store/mask-fitters" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Cadmus Dental</a> took almost a month to get me the two designs I ordered - the tall and premium fitters.</p>
<p><a href="https://masterlaboratories.com/product/bellus3d-mask-fitter/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Master Labs</a> took less than a week, but they’re local. I was only able to order the standard design from them.</p>
<p>I’m still waiting for the fitters I ordered from <a href="https://www.forecast3d.com/services/bellus3d-mask-fitter" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Forecast3D</a> but I think they’re on their way. If you’re in a hurry go with Master Labs.</p>
<p>All the fitters are printed from PLA plastic and seem pretty durable. The Standard fitter is all you need. All cost roughly $20 each.</p>
<p>This is me using the Master Labs Standard fitter over one of my homemade cloth masks.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="https://leo.fm/images/maskfitter.png" title=" Leo wearing the standard mask fitter " data-thumbnail="https://leo.fm/images/maskfitter.png" data-sub-html="<h2>Go ahead, come at me Covid!</h2><p> Leo wearing the standard mask fitter </p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Go ahead, come at me Covid!</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>According to Belus3D</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The NIH has listed the Bellus3D Mask Fitter as <a href="https://3dprint.nih.gov/discover/3dpx-013836" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">appropriate for clinical use</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>and</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The Loma Linda University School of Dentistry has worked with [Belus3d] on the development and testing of the Mask Fitter            and have found that it <a href="https://dentistry.llu.edu/about/school-news/llu-school-dentistry-and-bellus3d-collaborate-mask-solutions-during-covid-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">enhances the peripheral seal of a mask</a>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I wore a standard surgical mask with the fitter and a face shield to the grocery store yesterday and I felt <em>invulnerable</em>. Of course I sterilized the fitter and shield immediately afterwards, washed thoroughly, and tossed my clothes into the wash. My shoes are still on the steps outside. I know, I’m paranoid, but it’s not a lot of effort and I really don’t want to get or spread Covid-19!</p>
<p>I highly recommend these fitters. Wearing one protects me as well as it protects others.</p>
<p>OK this is the last time I’ll post about masks. I think I’ve covered the subject pretty thoroughly, and by now you know how I feel about them. If everyone wears a simple mask we can go back to life as usual <a href="https://www.axios.com/cdc-director-masking-coronavirus-dba00f19-4167-43a0-b021-9a9e66974517.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">in as little as a month</a>. Why wouldn’t you wear one?</p>
<p>And if it’s extra protection you’re after, put the Belus3D app on your iPhone X or later and make yourself a mask fitter!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>It’s Science, Buddy</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/07/science/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 11:27:21 -0700</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/07/science/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I keep finding articles describing why masks are important. This is from more than two months ago but it’s more important than ever.</p>
<p>Why simple cloth masks work best, from the Journal of <a href="https://aaqr.org/articles/aaqr-20-04-le-0154" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Aerosol and Air Quality Research</a><sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup></p>
<blockquote>
<p>By donning a homemade mask made of any 2-ply or more dense fabric, [Americans] would be able shrink their inhalation/exhalation radius immensely and  help stem the current outbreaks that are ravaging their country. In  addition, cloth masks can be tailor made to fit snugly and close the  gaping holes created by poorly fitting surgical masks. Furthermore, a  cloth mask can be easily decontaminated as it can be washed with  over-the-counter disinfectants, heated in an oven or treated by steam  sterilization above 70°C for longer than 5 mins, all proven methods to  effectively inactivate the SARS-CoV-2 virus (Chin <em>et al.</em>,  2020). Surgical masks are designed for single-use and can be  decontaminated by any of the above methods, including dry-heating in an  electric rice cooker (Lin <em>et al.</em>, 2017). However, the potential deformation and degraded effectiveness of the mask’s polymer layer after repeated treatments should be further evaluated. With that, the surgical masks are then thrown away and added to the mounting global  plastic pollution problem. Thus, the environmental cost of discarded  surgical masks is already being outlined and with the persistence of the COVID-19 pandemic and the slow, cautious transition back to normal,  this cost will grow unabated unless <strong>alternative mask usage is widely  promoted</strong>.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Still many of the people I see on the street are not wearing masks of any kind. And most of those who do are wearing poorly-fitted disposable surgical masks. Exactly the kind of mask this article is arguing against.</p>
<p>Since people seem unwilling to do anything to protect others, I’m going to have to take matters into my own hands by fully protecting myself whenever I go out using my own home-made PPE. Kind of like Jude Law in “<em>Contagion</em>” minus the oxygen tank.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/judelaw.jpg" title="Jude Law in his home-made PPE from the movie Contagion" data-thumbnail="/images/judelaw.jpg" data-sub-html="<h2>Jude Law in “Contagion</h2><p>Jude Law in his home-made PPE from the movie Contagion</p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">Jude Law in “Contagion</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>I’m still waiting for my <a href="https://leo.fm/2020/06/improved/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">3D printed mask fitter</a> to come from Cadmus Dental. When it arrives I believe I’ll be able to sew mask squares composed of two layers of cotton with chiffon or silk in between that will provide almost perfect protection and still remain highly breathable. I also have a yard of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B087PJDPCR/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_asin_title_o01_s00?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">meltblown polypropylene fabric</a> to try out.  Washing depletes the static charge on the chiffon, silk, or poly but virgourous ironing restores it. I iron all my masks after washing to further disinfect them. Plus putting on a freshly ironed mask is quite nice.</p>
<p>Wearing these masks with a face shield and coupled with apppropriate social distancing and hygiene I might be able to dodge this thing.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/leoprotected.png" title=" Leo wearing ball cap, homemade face mask, and face sheild. " data-thumbnail="/images/leoprotected.png" data-sub-html="<h2>My personal protection equipment</h2><p> Leo wearing ball cap, homemade face mask, and face sheild. </p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">My personal protection equipment</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>Our failed President said yesterday that <a href="https://www.cnn.com/2020/07/05/politics/donald-trump-july-4-coronavirus/index.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">99% of Covid cases are harmless</a>. That’s a lie. It is true that the mortality rate may be as low as 1% globally (still that’s 129,000 people in the US alone as of today), but according to the <a href="https://www.who.int/docs/default-source/coronaviruse/situation-reports/20200416-sitrep-87-covid-19.pdf?sfvrsn=9523115a_2" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">World Health Organization</a></p>
<blockquote>
<p>While the majority of patients with COVID-19 have mild or moderated illness, it is estimated that 20% of affected patients will need oxygen.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Seems serious to me. And we’re only starting to learn of the long-term damage caused by even mild cases.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>Buy or make cloth masks people, and wear them whenever you’re out of the house. It’s the only way through this.</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Hsiao, T.C., Chuang, H.C., Griffith, S.M., Chen, S.J. and Young, L.H.  (2020). COVID-19: An Aerosol&rsquo;s Point of View from Expiration to  Transmission to Viral-mechanism. <em>Aerosol Air Qual. Res.</em> 20:905-910. <a href="https://doi.org/10.4209/aaqr.2020.04.0154">https://doi.org/10.4209/aaqr.2020.04.0154</a> <a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Calculating mortality and risks during a pandemic is hard. But the New York Times  has a <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/07/05/us/politics/trump-coronavirus-factcheck.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">good article on the subject</a>. And the stories about healthy young people suffuring horrific consequences and even death are <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/nick-cordero-dead-bullets-broadway-waitress-actor-was-41-1301841" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">very scary</a>. <a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></description></item><item><title>The Hannibal Lecter Covid Mask</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/06/improved/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/06/improved/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Time for another mask iteration. Today on <a href="https://youtu.be/D6UQqlUMfiw?t=8231" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">MacBreak Weekly</a> Alex Lindsay recommended using a cool iPhone app to help make masks more effective.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.bellus3d.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Belus3D</a> is a free app for iOS that creates a 3D model of your head in a few seconds. I&rsquo;ve used it before and it&rsquo;s pretty amazing, but there never seemed to be anything useful to do with it. Until now.</p>
<p><figure><a class="lightgallery" href="/images/maskframe.gif" title=" Creepy 3D model of Leo&amp;rsquo;s head " data-thumbnail="/images/maskframe.gif" data-sub-html="<h2>A 3D model of my head with the mask fitter attached</h2><p> Creepy 3D model of Leo&amp;rsquo;s head </p>">
        
    </a><figcaption class="image-caption">A 3D model of my head with the mask fitter attached</figcaption>
    </figure></p>
<p>You can use the 3D model of your head to print a custom fitted plastic frame designed to make masks more effective. The idea is that the frame will hold down the mask fabric to make a better seal between the mask and the face. The frame has four t-mounts for elastic bands to hold the mask to your face.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve ordered a couple of different sizes (tall and premium) from <a href="https://www.cadmusdental.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Cadmus Dental</a> (you can do that from the Belus3D app). I&rsquo;ll let you know when they arrive and how well they work.</p>
<p>Next step, build a Leo clone so TWiT can continue forever! Mwa-ha-ha-ha!</p>]]></description></item><item><title>Masks Work</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/06/maskswork/</link><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/06/maskswork/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>Turns out not only that masks work, but they work better than social distancing and hand washing alone. If you&rsquo;re going out, wear a mask and don&rsquo;t take it off until you&rsquo;re back inside.</p>
<p>From a peer-reviewed<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> article in <a href="https://www.pnas.org/content/early/2020/06/10/2009637117" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">The Proceedings of the NAS</a> - <em>Identifying airborne transmission as the dominant route for the spread of COVID-19</em>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Our analysis reveals that the difference with and without mandated face  covering represents the determinant in shaping the trends of the  pandemic. <strong>This protective measure significantly reduces the number of  infections.</strong> Other mitigation measures, such as social distancing  implemented in the United States, are insufficient by themselves in  protecting the public.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It turns out SARS-CoV-2 virus is particularly virulent when aerosolized.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>While transmission via direct or indirect contact occurs in a short  range, airborne transmission via aerosols can occur over an extended  distance and time. Inhaled virus-bearing aerosols deposit directly along the human respiratory tract.</p>
</blockquote>
<p></p>
<p>Transmission by aerosol is the last pathway for the virus that we haven&rsquo;t stopped with hand-washing and social distancing, and it might be the most virulent form.</p>
<p><em>Please</em> wear your mask whenever you&rsquo;re outside. Don&rsquo;t take it off just because there&rsquo;s no one around. The aerosolized virus can float in the air for hours and infect anyone who inhales it.</p>
<p>Masks don&rsquo;t show weakness, they show intelligence. Be smart, wear your mask! 😷</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>Wait a minute. Now there’s <a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/06/18/health/coronavirus-retractions-studies.html?smtyp=cur&amp;smid=tw-nytimesscience" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">some issue with the paper</a> and its peer-review. The problem seems to be that the paper overstates the importance of masks relative to other mitigations. Furthermore, there’s still debate over the path of infection. Some scientists say this paper overstates the evidence that aerosolized particles are the primary vector. <a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></description></item><item><title>Making Masks</title><link>https://leo.fm/2020/06/makingmasks/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>Author</author><guid>https://leo.fm/2020/06/makingmasks/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>New research shows that wearing masks makes a difference. But we <em>all</em> have to do it!</p>
<p>According to <a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/06/200609190727.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Science Daily</a>, reporting on a study from the University of Cambridge:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>The widespread use of face masks keeps the coronavirus reproduction number below 1.0, and prevents further waves when combined with lockdowns, new research suggests. A modeling study from the universities of Cambridge and Greenwich indicates that <a href="https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rspa.2020.0376" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">lockdowns alone will not stop the resurgence of COVID-19</a>. Researchers say <strong>even homemade masks with limited effectiveness can dramatically reduce transmission rates</strong> if worn by enough people, regardless of whether they show symptoms.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I love making my own masks. I even bought a sewing machine to do it (the inexpensive <a href="https://www.mybernette.com/en-US/3-Series/Bernette-35.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Bernina Bernett b35</a>, now sold out everywhere!) With a little practice you can make a mask like this:</p>
<p></p>
<p>It&rsquo;s taken me a while to perfect this mask, but I love it because</p>
<ol>
<li>it&rsquo;s relatively easy to make</li>
<li>it&rsquo;s convenient to wear and take off</li>
<li>fit is snug and almost airtight</li>
<li>it&rsquo;s effective</li>
</ol>
<p>I started with this video then made some improvements:</p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube-nocookie.com/embed/zm_NmpdgWWA" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>One of the nicest features of this mask is how you tie it. There&rsquo;s one length of cord<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1</a></sup> that goes around your neck and ties at the top of the head. It&rsquo;s effectively a drawstring which helps fit the mask snugly as you tie it. The neck loop is handy because you can take off the mask but leave it hanging around your neck for quick donning.<sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2</a></sup></p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve made some changes to the mask that makes it more comfortable and, I believe, more effective.</p>
<p>First the materials. In the video the designer recommends two layers with a filter pocket. I tried this using high-threadcount cotton for the outer layer <sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3</a></sup> and old t-shirts for the inner layer. The t-shirts are soft and comfortable but the pouch opening hits right at the mouth and kind of bothers me. And adding a filter layer (I tried vacuum cleaner bags and paper towels) really reduces breathe-ability. This is key; <strong>if it&rsquo;s not easy to breathe in a mask you won&rsquo;t wear it.</strong></p>
<p>After reading about research from the <a href="https://www.sciencedaily.com/releases/2020/04/200424081648.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">American Chemical Society</a> about the effectiveness of various materials for mask making:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>One layer of a tightly woven cotton sheet combined with two layers of  polyester-spandex chiffon &ndash; a sheer fabric often used in evening gowns  &ndash; filtered out the most aerosol particles (80-99%, depending on  particle size), with performance close to that of an N95 mask material.  Substituting the chiffon with natural silk or flannel, or simply using a cotton quilt with cotton-polyester batting, produced similar results.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I decided to eliminate the superfluous filter pouch and replace the t-shirt cotton with <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01FNDH3EY/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">silk charmeuse</a>. It feels better, it&rsquo;s much easier to sew, and the breathe-ability is excellent. Come winter, and yes I expect us to still be wearing masks this winter, I&rsquo;ll replace the silk with flannel.</p>
<p>To help seal the nose area I use <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01NAO56KH/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">peel and stick tin ties</a>, the kind used to seal up coffee bags at the grocery store. I experimented with these by ripping them off all our coffee bags, but it turns out you can buy them by the hundred on Amazon, so no more open coffee bags at the Laporte house.</p>
<p>Sealing the nose well is important for mask effectiveness and to keep my glasses from steaming up. If I&rsquo;m not wearing glasses I&rsquo;m wearing <a href="https://www.amazon.com/LOHONER-Medical-Student-Protective-Anti-Fog/dp/B0868NZ714/ref=sr_1_1?crid=12MUP5K8ER3IS&amp;dchild=1&amp;keywords=lab&#43;goggles&amp;qid=1591801164&amp;s=home-garden&amp;sprefix=lab&#43;goggl%2Cgarden%2C217&amp;sr=1-1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">protective lab goggles</a>. Keeping the mouth, nose, and eyes protected from aerosolized virus particles is the goal here.</p>
<p>To soften the edges of the mask and block leaks around the edges, I have started folding all four edges in over a small strip of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00F8MRLBG/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">cotton quilt batting</a>.</p>

<p>The batting adds some structure and softness to the edges and, as I learned when I used it as a layer in one of my masks, is practically impermeable. The mask on the left is for my mom. At 87-years-old she finds it hard to tie the string behind her head so I replaced it with <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08793W5R8/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">elastic</a>.</p>
<p>These masks are light, comfortable, and breathe-able. I don&rsquo;t have any evidence that they&rsquo;re more effective than any other mask, but I like to think so.</p>
<p>Want to make your own masks? Here&rsquo;s what you need:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.mybernette.com/en-US/3-Series/Bernette-35.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Bernina Bernett b35</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07PZH9R23/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Fiskar&rsquo;s Sewing Essentials Kit</a></li>
<li><a href="https://sewingarts.com/collections/fat-quarters" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Cotton Fabric</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01FNDH3EY/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Silk Charmeuse</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004NLJXYQ/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_image?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Cotton Clothesline Rope</a> or <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B08793W5R8/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Elastic Cord</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B01NAO56KH/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Peel-and-stick Tin Ties</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B00F8MRLBG/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Cotton Quilt Batting</a></li>
</ul>
<p>Make &lsquo;em, wear &lsquo;em and remember, <em>I wear a mask to protect you; you wear a mask to protect me</em>. ❤️</p>
<section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
<hr>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
<p>I use a 60 inch length of <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B004NLJXYQ/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_image?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">soft cotton clothesline rope</a>. You can also use <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07C29GGMZ/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">paracord</a> or this really cool <a href="https://www.amazon.com/gp/product/B07P9DM6FY/ref=ppx_yo_dt_b_search_asin_title?ie=UTF8&amp;psc=1" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Bohemia ethnic thread</a> a listener recommended. <a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
<p>This freaks out some people because they figure the outer part of the mask might be covered with covid. But if it is, then so is my shirt, hair, etc. The trick is to keep the virus from your mouth, nose, and eyes. So wash your hands after you touch the mask. And if you&rsquo;re that worried strip down when you get home and hop in the shower! These masks are <em>not</em> used the same way masks would be worn in a hospital. In a medical setting the mask is designed to protect the medical worker from an infected patient. We wear our masks to protect others from us. They also help keep us from touching our face when out and about. <a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
<li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
<p>I use quilting fabric from Sewing Arts in Santa Monica. A <a href="https://sewingarts.com/collections/fat-quarters" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">fat-quarter bundle</a> can make 40 masks and costs as little as $50. The patterns are really nice, too. <a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&#x21a9;&#xfe0e;</a></p>
</li>
</ol>
</section>]]></description></item></channel></rss>